RYAN BOWDRE

Full-Stack Web Developer

CELL | [323] 640-0168

EMAIL | ryanbowdre@gmail.com

LINKEDIN | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanbowdre/

GITHUB | https://github.com/RyanBowdre

PORTFOLIO LINK | https://ryanbowdre.github.io./

Summary

Skills

Full-Stack web developer with a passion for web development using Javascript and the MEAN stack. Striving to utilize my education and training from Coding Dojo, along with my 3 1/2+ years of software industry web development testing experience, to serve a team in a front-end web development position.

FRONT-END

JavaScript

JQuery

HTML5

CSS3

AngularJS

Bootstrap

BACK-END

Node.JS

Django

Flask

Ruby on Rails

ExpressJS

DATABASES

MongoDB

MySQL

NoSQL

SQLite

SOFTWARE

JIRA

Git

MISC

Agile / Scrum

Job Experience

Web Development QA Tester | Age of Learning Inc.

Glendale | Dec 2014 - July 2017

Performed Functional & Data Analytics Web Testing - Utilized functional and technical design documents to create test plans within the QTEST database; performed functional / data analytics testing across all browsers (Chrome, FireFox, IE, Safari) and identified / documented software problems using JIRA.

Promotion - Promoted from QA tester to imbedded Web Dev QA tester for displaying leadership skills and demonstrating a thorough understanding of QA Web Development testing processes and systems.

Coordinated Scrum Meetings - Worked directly with producers / developers to discuss bug fixes, testing cycle progress, and project priority; delivered presentations for new website features to department leaders.

Created Git Deploy Tool Testing Environments - Created, utilized, and maintained dev sandboxes and testing environments using Git Deploy tool; used Git branches and repositories to sync out artwork, database entries, etc.

Software QA Tester | Disney Interactive Studios

Glendale | July 2013 - Dec 2014

Performed Functional Web / Mobile Testing - Executed project test plans across mobile devices (Apple / Android, phones / tablets) as well as all browsers (Chrome, FireFox, IE, Safari) to identify / document software problems and their causes using JIRA.

Projects (to view additional projects, view my GitHub / Portfolio)

Pacman: Quest for the Keys! - Web Game - JavaScript / HTML / CSS A web based Pacman-inspired game built using JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, and CSS.

Education

Coding Dojo

Glendale | Aug 2017 - Dec 2017

Completed intensive 16 week, full-time web development training program; developed full web applications using Javascript, Ruby and Python. Over 1000 hours of coding experience gained.

Loyola Marymount University | Computer Science

Los Angeles | May 2010 - Aug 2012

Relevant coursework: Programming Laboratory | Data Structures | Algorithms | Logic Design